AradhanaSharma

LinkedIn · aradhana.sharma@outlook.com · +1 510 738 7860

A Project manager and Agilist with 9+ years of experience working with diverse cross-cultural global teams in various projects spanning across domains in technology and marketplace. It hrive in the strategic long term vision and consistently demonstrate effective project management keeping data driven outlook.

Experience

Kaodim · Project Manager

NOV 2017 - FEB 2019 • SELANGOR, MALAYSIA

Built & develop 15+ personnel Engineering team for Web & mobile apps program management across 4 countries.

- Maximizing business value with scrum (later Kanban) by establishing 2 POD structure, including CI/CD and streamlining processes across company.
- Optimized release cycle by analyzing project metrics like velocity charts, defects reports, release charts etc.
- Reduced issues resolution time by 40% via central issue priority platform.
- Effectively drive team towards KPI goals by coaching and mentoring, timely project updates, change management and monitor quality deliveries.

Monotype · Program Manager

FEB 2015 - JUL 2017 • NOIDA, INDIA

Established 4 cross-platform project teams across 3 countries

Product CIM (Olapic)

- Build in-house team of 8+ animators / designers across India and NY, which became a new revenue stream for the company.
- Established Kanban process with live-dashboards, integrating risk and change management frameworks, aligning all stakeholders and teams.
- Generated \$1.2MARR, resulted in 60% reduction in clients' production costs and 2X engagement on campaigns.
- 60% less release time by optimizing development cycle & reduce waste.

Product Linotype & Monotype.com

- Setup new teams for <u>linotype.com</u> § <u>monotype.com</u> (5+) in India §
 Germany, saving ~ \$30K in operations by efficient capacity planning.
- Responsible for hiring tech talent and mentoring. Effectively managed multiple teams with 6 team members each.
- Coaching teams in technical decisions for cloud & platform migration.
- Established scrum processes and communication channels in product \$
 engineering teams across 3 countries to deliver quality releases.

Others: Launched Monotype India's blogging and social media strategy.

HCL Technologies · Manager-Web Engineering

MAY 2011 - JAN 2015 • NOIDA, INDIA

Led 3+ personnel web engineering team under corporate marketing.

- Derive the construct and operations of web engineering projects with internal teams and vendor team to deliver timely and quality deliveries.
- Established effective communication platform, change management, requirements gathering process for Digital CoE.
- Hands-on development using Linux, Drupal, Mysql & PHP.

Srijan Technologies · Lead Developer

2007 - 2011 • GURGAON, INDIA

Project architect and lead developer for client projects, worked on DRUPAL, PHP, MYSQL for award winning websites like mnn.com, thegiving point.org etc.

Notables

Leadership @Monotype

Member of the core leadership team to take strategic and business decisions in Monotype India.

Certifications

- CSM ScrumAlliance
- CSPO ScrumAlliance
- Usability Analyst HFI

Agile Coach

Coached tech, operations and marketing teams for Scrum / Kanban in Monotype & Kaodim.

PMI

Selected as New generation Leader representative from SF chapter for PMI's Global Region 7 conference, 2020.

Skills

Project: Agile methodologies

- · Leadership Planning and organizing · Budget mngmt · Critical thinking · Goal Oriented · Risk & Change mngmnt
- · Stakeholder mngmnt

Product: Mobile Apps · Business analysis

- \cdot Strategy/Roadmap \cdot UAT \cdot User research
- \cdot Wireframing \cdot Usability testing

Technical: AWS · PHP · SQL · Linux · JQuery · Nodejs · Python · Web Technologies

Tools: JIRA · Trello · Google Analytics

- · Pivotal Tracker · TFS · Confluence
- · Microstrategy · Tableau · SAS · MS Excel· Lucid Chart · Microsoft Visio

Education

Golden Gate University (2019-20)

Masters in IT Management (GPA 4.0)

XLRI Jamshedpur (2012-13)

Post-grad cert in Business Management

Punjab Technical Univ, (2003-07)

Bachelor of Technology in Computer Science Engineering